# **Daniel Vargas**

Montreal, Quebec, Canada



devg28@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/danvargg



4389243331



https://github.com/danvargg

## Summary

Daniel is a Machine Learning Engineer with over 8+ years (16+ overall) of experience delivering predictive analytics solutions to solve business problems in multiple industries. Though Data Science, Machine Learning and Deep Learning, he has excelled in solving Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing (NLP) problems. He is highly regarded for his ability to design, develop, optimize, and operationalize (MLOPs) machine learning models that deliver business value and competitive advantage for his clients and employers.

Main tech stack: Python, SQL, Tensorflow-Keras, Pytorch, Scikit-Learn, Transformers, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Git, Github, fastAPI, Docker.

### **Experience**



#### Lead, Al Development

Innodem Neurosciences

Feb 2021 - Mar 2023 (2 years 2 months)

- Conducted code refactoring (Python) to improve overall codebase quality, readability, accessibility and maintainability, ensuring PEP-8 and OOP practices in the process
- Implemented comprehensive unit tests and code coverage for the deep learning pipeline, ensuring that the system is reliable and robust
- Ensured compliance with Software of Unknown Provenance (SOUP) regulations, ensuring that all software components used in the system were adequately evaluated for quality and security
- Ensured compliance with electronic personal health information (ePHI) privacy and security regulations: HIPAA, PIPEDA, and GDPR
- Ensured that codebase, systems, documentation, and processes comply with ISO 27001
- Collaborated with the SCRUM process, facilitating daily stand-ups, sprint planning, retrospective meetings, and ensuring that the team is adhering to agile principles and best practices
- Conducted code reviews, ensuring that code quality standards were met and that the codebase is maintainable and scalable
- Defined, planned, and assigned tasks to team members, ensuring that each team member has a clear understanding of their responsibilities and deadlines
- Managed priorities, ensuring that the team is working on the most critical and impactful features for the business
- Completed federal government R&D grant documents, securing funding for the project and ensuring that all documentation requirements were met
- Developed CI/CD pipelines for machine learning code unit tests and quality

#### **→ MASTER** Data Science Consultant

Master Data Analysis Sep 2020 - Mar 2023 (2 years 7 months)

- Developed and facilitated a comprehensive data science training program for a team of 9 data analysts, covering topics ranging from data extraction to model deployment, resulting in a significant increase in team members' technical proficiency and ability to deliver results
- Coached and mentored data science projects, providing guidance and expert advise to ensure that business results were achieved
- Developed all program materials, including code, presentations, assignments, and projects, resulting in a cohesive and effective training program that met the needs of the team and the organization
- Setup Azure infrastructure for sessions and projects

### Deep Learning Engineer

#### Innodem Neurosciences

Feb 2019 - Jan 2021 (2 years)

- Trained and improved neural network (CNN) models for eye-tracking applications (Tensorflow and Scikit-Learn)
- Developed and implemented model deployment capabilities for both on-server (ONNX, TFLite) and on-the-edge (CoreML, iOS) scenarios
- Optimized deployed model inference to achieve real-time eye gaze predictions on-device
- Created and operationalized the end-to-end deep learning pipeline that covers data processing, model building, model training and evaluation, and model deployment
- Designed and implemented the core neural network (ResNet) architecture and training pipeline for diagnostics applications
- Designed and implemented neural network experiments tracking to make informed decisions based on data
- Developed on-device model fine-tuning (transfer learning) code to enable personalized predictions for individual users
- Developed image processing algorithms to improve models training and inference metrics

## Sr. Business Systems Analyst (Operational Techonology)

CN

Mar 2018 - Dec 2018 (10 months)

- Elicited / gathered, clarified, documented, analyzed, prioritized, and decomposed business requirements (process and tools) from internal and external partners, within an agile and continuous delivery environment
- Elicited and translated business requirements into process and solution requirements
- Acted as liaison between business and implementation teams
- Lead portion of the strategic roadmap defined by the Product Manager
- Performed process analyses and improvements backlog assessments (DMAIC, PMCS)
- Shaped the requirement phase based on client dependencies and scope
- Created and validated current and future-state processes and tools with business partners



#### **Machine Learning Engineer**

Crowdbotics

Nov 2017 - Apr 2018 (6 months)

- Developed a recommendation algorithm and model for an audio streaming service for wellness content, leveraging machine learning techniques to provide personalized recommendations to users

- Designed and implemented the algorithm using state-of-the-art machine learning libraries and frameworks, resulting in a high-performance and accurate model

### **Continuous Improvement Specialist (ITPLM)**

#### BOMBARDIER

Aug 2014 - Mar 2018 (3 years 8 months)

- Coached and lead continuous improvement projects and workshops (VSM, visual management systems, kaizen, decision-based-schedules, knowledge diagrams, etc.):
- Challenged current business processes and mindset to ensure sustainable improvements
- Developed visual management systems (e.g. engineering design update and release, parts serialization)
- Identified the framework for data migration project
- Supported a 'Hansei' for software development project
- Visualized and eliminated waste through Value Stream Mapping (VSM) projects
- Identified root causes by performing formal technical problem solving and root cause analysis

#### **⊘**baseline Data Scientist

baseline.io

Nov 2017 - Dec 2017 (2 months)

- Developed a dashboard application to track, visualize, and analyze mobile telemetry data, providing insights into user behavior and system performance
- Designed and implemented the application using modern data visualization libraries, resulting in a highly interactive and user-friendly interface



#### Data Scientist

SciBase.co

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017 (4 months)

- Designed and implemented an initial authors disambiguation algorithm and model using Natural Language Processing (NLP) techniques to accurately identify and disambiguate authors with similar or identical names
- Conducted extensive research and analysis to identify the most appropriate NLP techniques and algorithms to use in the development of the disambiguation model

#### Lean Six Sigma Black Belt Consultant

QualityGB

Jul 2012 - Dec 2012 (6 months)

### 

Johnson & Johnson

Nov 2010 - Jul 2012 (1 year 9 months)

#### Manufacturing Engineer

Jul 2009 - Nov 2010 (1 year 5 months)

## Process Engineering Supervisor

Andin International
Jun 2008 - Apr 2009 (11 months)

### Intermodal and Equipment Control Coordinator

A.P. Moller - Maersk Jul 2007 - Jun 2008 (1 year)

#### **Education**

## coursera Coursera

Machine Learning Engineering for Production (MLOps) Specialization - DeepLearning.AI, MLOps

Nov 2021 - Nov 2021

https://github.com/danvargg/danvargg/blob/main/docs/certificates/dlai\_mlops\_spec.pdf

## coursera Coursera

Deep Learning Specialization - DeepLearning.AI, Deep Learning Mar 2018 - Mar 2018 https://github.com/danvargg/danvargg/blob/main/docs/certificates/dlia\_dl\_spec.pdf

## Johns Hopkins University Advanced Academic Programs

Data Science Specialization, Data Science
Jan 2017 - Jun 2017
https://github.com/danvargg/danvargg/blob/main/docs/certificates/jh\_ds\_spec.pdf

## University of Ottawa

Master of Engineering (MEng), Engineering Management 2013 - 2014

## 5 Instituto Tecnológico de Santo Domingo

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Industrial Engineering 2004 - 2008

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

Azure Data Scientist Associate - Microsoft

Issued Nov 2020 - Expires Nov 2022 H573-8605

## Microsoft Professional Program in Artificial Intelligence - Microsoft

087e74e3-4731-49db-9eef-583aa44de2bf

## **Skills**

Communication • Artificial Intelligence (AI) • Deep Learning • Machine Learning • Data Science • TensorFlow • Scikit-Learn • PyTorch • Data Analysis • JIRA